(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-10T04:59:59.034317",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
以心伝心ポーズチャレンジ！お題は！
Telepathy Pose Challenge! The prompt is...
警察官
Police officer!
あ、簡単
Ah, easy.
あ、そうだよね？
Right, right?
せーの！
Ready, go!
ふっ、ふっ
Fu, fu!
は！？
Huh!?
何それ？
What's that?
敬礼？
Salute?
拳銃？
Handgun?
ねえ、おかしい！絶対違ってるよ！
Hey, that's weird! That's totally wrong!
ドクター
Doctor!
難しえ……
That's tough...
え、でもこれはもう、ね、あれしかないよね？
Eh, but for this, there's only one thing, right?
せーの！
Ready, go!
は！？
Huh!?
え？何してんの？
Eh? What are you doing?
なんかさ、ネットでよくあるやつ、あのこうやってお医者さんが……
Like, you know that common internet thing where doctors...
あ、箱のやつ？
Ah, the box thing?
うん、箱のやつ。え、ドクターかな？
Yeah, the box thing. Eh, is it doctor?
こっちでしょ？あっ、聴診器、聴診器、聴診器。
This way, right? Ah, stethoscope, stethoscope, stethoscope.
わかんないよ。
I don't know.
いっぱいいる、今いっ、今いっぱいいるからね！
There are so many, there are so many right now!
はい、とくいで。
Okay, expert mode.
せーの！
Ready, go!
あー！いや違ったー！やっとあった！
Ahー! No, wrong! Yayー! We finally got it!
やっとだ、やっとだよ！
We finally got it, finally!
お寿司屋さん
Sushi chef!
いや、これさすがにしよ。
Well, this has gotta be matching.
せーの！
Ready, go!
えっ？えっ？
Eh? Eh?
いや、お寿司ざんまい。
Well, Zanmai Sushi.
おっ、寿司握ってる。
Oh, holding sushi.
はあ！
Hah!?
えー！？
Eh!?
え、でも大得意！
Eh, but I'm an expert!
せーの！
Ready, go!
え、なんか、コーラ振るやつ？
Eh, like, shaking cola?
あ、そういうことか！
Ah, that's what it was!
以心伝心ポーズチャレンジ！お題は！
Telepathy Pose Challenge! The prompt is...
バスケットボール
Basketball!
よっし、よっしよ。
Alright, alright.
せーの！
Ready, go!
やった！
We did it!
めちゃらしくあったわ。
That was super fitting.
サッカー
Soccer!
どっちだろ？
Which one is it?
あ、待ってそっかどっち、お前どっちだ？どっちだ！
Ah, wait, right, which one, which one are you? Which one!
せーの！はい！
Ready, go! Yes!
これ、ゴールキーパー。
This is goalkeeper.
え、自分もこれ、ゴールキーパー！
Eh, I was also doing this, goalkeeper!
ハンディキャップじゃないな。
That's not handicap.
いやいや、上でしょう！
No, no, it's upper!
これもどっちだ？
Which one is this too?
せーの！
Ready, go!
はい、無理。え、待ってでも合ってるよね？
Yes, impossible. Eh, wait, but it's right, right?
でもさ、あれ投げるのだよね？
But like, throwing and catching, right?
そう、投げる。
Right, throwing.
あははは！以心伝心はできてないけど！
Ahahaha! Telepathy wasn't achieved, though!
チアリーディング
Cheerleading!
あ、でもやったことある。
Ah, but I've done it before.
え、マジで？
Eh, seriously?
イメージでやるわ。
I'll do it by image.
うん。いくよ。せーの！
Yeah. Here we go. Ready, go!
え、でも大体合ってっね？
Eh, but mostly right, right?
一緒じゃない？
Isn't it the same?
いやいや、いっ、いいじゃんいいじゃん！90%ぐらい。
No no, i-, it's fine, it's fine! Like 90%.
eスポーツ
eSports
え、え、え？これっ、スポーツ……だけど
Eh, eh, eh? This is, sports... though
せーの！
Ready, go!
え、嘘、え、嘘、これさ、パソコンだよね？パソコンみるしか！
Eh, no way, no way, this is like, a PC, right? Only looking at a PC!
しかもめっちゃモニター近くね？せーの！……
And the monitor is so close! Ready, go! ...
以心伝心ポーズチャレンジ！お題は！
Telepathy Pose Challenge! The prompt is...
わかる。
I know.
アイドル
Idol!
せーの！
Ready, go!
え、一緒じゃない？
Eh, isn't it the same?
え？
Eh?
星じゃない？
Isn't it a star?
そう、星！
Right, a star!
ボディビルダー
Bodybuilder
どれか？
Which one?
せーの！
Ready, go!
あー！あーい、無理ー！
Ahー! A-hi, impossibleー!
は？難しくね？
Huh? Isn't it hard?
難しくね？
Isn't it hard?
せーの、はい！
Ready, go, yes!
え、突っ込み、突っ込みどころはやし？
Eh, tsukkomi, tsukkomi point is hayashi?
歴史上の偉人
Historical figure
誰が考えたの？
Who came up with this?
プロデューサー？
Producer?
どうしようかな？
What should I do?
せーの！
Ready, go!
それ誰？それの。
Who is that? That one.
わかんないけど偉そうな人。待って、我が輩もわかんないけど偉そうな人。
I don't know, but someone important-looking. Wait, I don't know either, but someone important-looking.
前のやつもさ、考える形一緒。
The previous one too, the way we thought was the same.
殿？
Lord?
え、殿？殿？
Eh, Lord? Lord?
わからん。
I don't know.
せーの！
Ready, go!
殿？
Lord?
わからん。
I don't know.
さっきと一緒じゃん。
It's the same as earlier.
でも、これなんか偉そうな、偉そうになってるとね。
But, this is like, looking important, getting all high and mighty.
そう。
Right.
これは何それ？
What is this?
我が輩はちょっと座ってる感じで。
I'm sitting down a bit.
ヤンキー？
Yankee?
ヤンキーじゃないよ！ヤンキーよ、頭、頭が4つ合ってるじゃん、なんか殿はさ。
That's not Yankee! Yankee, the head, four heads match, right, like the lord.
以心伝心ポーズチャレンジ！お題は！
Telepathy Pose Challenge! The prompt is...
猫
Cat
せーの！
Ready, go!
なんだよそれ！
What is that!
いや、これさ、やばい、玄関前待機してんのよ。
Well, this, oh no, waiting in front of the entrance.
いや、猫って言ったらこれニャンニャンポーズでしょ？
No, when you say cat, this is the Nyan-Nyan pose, right?
いや、ニャンニャン、そんなポーズしねえよ！
No, Nyan-Nyan, I don't do that pose!
犬
Dog
いける？
Can you do it?
せーの！
Ready, go!
え、何これ！？正座！？正座すご！
Eh, what is this!? Seiza!? Seiza is amazing!
龍
Dragon
見たことないんだよね。
I've never seen one before.
自分……
Myself...
せーの！
Ready, go!
えーだって、こうやってドラゴンって手が短いじゃん？
Eh, because, dragons have short hands, right?
え、ほらここ、こうやって、こうやるでしょ？
Eh, look here, like this, doing this, right?
待って、関係ありますよ。
Wait, it's related.
せーの！
Ready, go!
ほっ！
Hop!
あ、犬じゃん！犬だって！
Ah, it's a dog! It's a dog!
これ難しい！
This is hard!
犬じゃん！犬じゃん！何これ！？
It's a dog! It's a dog! What is this!?
蝶々
Butterfly
え、一致するとさあ。
Eh, when it matches...
さすがにさ。
Naturally.
せーの！
Ready, go!
なんで閉じでんの？
Why are you closing it?
違う違う違う違う！ほらさ、手で手のやつ！
No no no no! Look, the hand thing!
さあ！
Now!
こうやって、こうやるっしょ。
You do it like this, like that.
以心伝心ポーズチャレンジ！お題は！
Telepathy Pose Challenge! The prompt is...
魔法少女
Magical girl
あ、でもいっぱいいるよね。
Ah, but there are lots, right?
せーの！
Ready, go!
杖持ってる、こうやって。
Holding a wand, like this.
魔法少女じゃ？
A magical girl?
それ少女じゃないよ。魔女じゃん。
That's not a girl. That's a witch.
え？うそ、うそ。
Eh? No way, no way.
天使も違うな。
An angel isn't right either.
せーの！
Ready, set!
パタパタパタって... 全然意味わかんねぇ。
Flapping around... I totally don't get it.
小悪魔。あーなんかわかるわ。せーの！
Little devil. Ah, I kind of get this. Ready, set!
あー、待って、それや！
Ah, wait, that's it!
え、これじゃね？え、それだわ。
Wait, isn't it this? Ah, that's it.
なんもマジでなんも浮かばなくてちょっとセクシーな感じ。なんも浮かばん。で、絶対これや。
I literally couldn't think of anything, just a slightly sexy vibe. Nothing came to mind. But it's definitely this.
怪盗。えー。
Phantom thief. Eh.
さっきこんなん見たこと。せーの！
I saw something like this earlier. Ready, set!
待て、何それ？これ、怪盗キッドさ。
Wait, what's that? This is Kaitou Kid.
え、自分も怪盗キッドやん！
Eh, I'm Kaitou Kid too!
やった！やった！
Yay! Yay!
いろんな手も入れるからな。
I'm putting in all sorts of poses.
せーの！
Ready, set!
うん、これはなんか、あのちょっと昔の漫画家さんのイメージ。ペン持ってる。
Yeah, this is like... an old-school manga artist image. Holding a pen.
普通に書いてる。
Just writing normally.
何のひねりもない。何のひねりもない、ただただなんか。
Zero twist. Absolutely no twist, just... you know.
だめだあ。くそー！
No good. Damn it!
以心伝心ポーズチャレンジ！お題は！
Telepathy Pose Challenge! The theme is!
あーや、うちいるんでね。
Ah, I'm right here.
わかる。
I know.
せーの！
Ready, set!
っ、何それ？あっ、刀出してる。
What's that? Ah, drawing a sword.
えっ、自分もバッド？
Wait, I had a bat?
似てる気が...くっそ、はじけよ、名前が。
Feels similar... Damn it, blow it, the name.
あっ、シャチ。これなに？これロックスでくるわ。
Ah, killer whale. What's this? This is coming from rocks.
せーの！
Ready, set!
え、はず。なにそれ？
Eh, embarassing. What is that?
で、これシャチの、その、あっ、じゃあ、あっ、頭の部分だった。あの、なんか、いや、いいや。想像で
And this is the killer whale's, um, ah, right, the head part. Um, well, nah, whatever. Just imagining
いや、いいや。
No, whatever.
行くよ。せーの！
Here we go. Ready, set!
うわっ！
Whoa!
なんか、これにししかワンビジョンいけよ。
Man, you gotta go with one vision on this.
鹿。はい。
Deer. Yes.
せーの！
Ready, set!
えへへ！
Ehehe!
はね、跳ねてです。
Jumping, it's jumping.
跳ねてです！
It's jumping!
一緒！
Together!
跳ねてです！
It's jumping!
秘密結社の総帥！
Secret society commander!
はい。
Yes.
え、なか。どれだろ？
Eh, inside. Which one could it be?
いやわかるだろ、隣にいるだろ。
You should know, I'm right next to you.
せーの！
Ready, set!
え、一緒じゃない？
Eh, aren't they the same?
あっ、ジャンプしろよ！
Hey, jump!
うわっ！
Whoa!
え、なんか、これじゃん！やった！
Eh, like, this is it! Yay!
以心伝心ポーズチャレンジ！お題は！
Telepathy Pose Challenge! The theme is!
いっぱいやるぞ。
We're doing a lot.
せーの！
Ready, set!
うわ、落ちた！
Whoa, I fell!
可愛いポーズ。
Cute pose.
ちょっと楽しみだな。行こう。
I'm kind of excited. Let's go.
いこう！
Let's go!
せーの！
Ready, set!
え？
Eh?
っ、えっ、てなに？
Wait, what's that?
可愛い。
Cute.
っ、可愛いだろ！
Cute, right!
逃げたな。
You ran away.
逃げでねえよ！
I didn't run away!
セクシーなポーズ。
Sexy pose.
せーの！
Ready, set!
うわ、ちょっとそれテクすぎだって。
Whoa, that's way too technical.
なあ、脇、見せるんだよ。
Hey, you're supposed to show your armpits.
あっさいんだからちょっと合わせてよ。
It's shallow, so match me a bit.
え、こんなん？
Eh, like this?
ええ？
Huh?
せーの！
Ready, set!
はーっ、腕組んでる！
Ha, you're crossing your arms!
腕組んでる！
You're crossing your arms!
よっしゃ！
All right!
いっしょ、いっしょ！やった！
Same, same! Yay!
はっ？可愛いポーズと一緒だろ！
Huh? That's the same as the cute pose!
似てるね。
They're similar.
せーの！
Ready, set!
おい、あれ、足見せてる。
Hey, look, she's showing her legs.
えろ、えろ、えろ、それ
Lewd, lewd, lewd, that
え、これハート？ハート？
Eh, is this a heart? A heart?
そう。
Yeah.
エロポーズじゃなくて？
Isn't it a lewd pose?
エロポーズじゃねえよ！そっちじゃねえよ、えなこがやるやつじゃねえよ！
It's not a lewd pose! Not that kind, it's not what Enako would do!
そっちだろ、エロポーズは。
That *is* a lewd pose.
直風に揺られて 何も考えずに
Swaying in the direct wind, without a single thought,
ただ相撲を眺めて 過ごすのもいいよね
just watching sumo wrestling and passing the time is nice too.
誰もが何かしら 運命を抱えてる
Everyone carries some kind of fate with them.
ただそれだけの事 悩むのはもうやめた
I've finally stopped worrying about just that.
さざなみの 音に癒されてく
Healed by the sound of ripples,
奇跡を運ぶ風のね 時を閉じ込めて
capturing the time of the wind that carries miracles.
シャイニングスター綴れば 夢に眠る幻が
If I string together a shining star, illusions sleeping in dreams
手のひらに降り注ぐ 新たな世界へ
will pour down onto my palms into a brand new world.
アビリボマインセセーゾ 果てしない道の向こうで
Beyond the endless road of my belief mindset,
瞬きの裏に映ろう 一粒の光
a single grain of light reflects behind my blinking eyes.
ときめきを感じて
Feeling the excitement.
あなたが触れるすべて 幸せであるように
May everything you touch be filled with happiness.
今生きる喜びを 忘れてしまわないよう
So that you never forget the joy of living right now,
月の光 隠す雲は揺らぎ
The clouds hiding the moonlight sway,
自由の翼は 今も大空をかける
and the wings of freedom still soar across the vast sky.
シャイニングスター綴れば 無限の今
If I string together a shining star, an infinite present—
言葉がまだ出なくてさ
Words aren't even out yet,
帰り道ひとり 空を見ている
walking home alone, looking at the sky.
届かない この想い
This feeling won't reach you.
どうしようもない夢を見ていた
Having a hopeless dream.
あなたとなら幸せが見えるかもなんて
Thinking happiness might be in sight if I'm with you...
届けてよ 叶えてよ
Deliver it, make it come true,
消せない気持ち 奇跡を呼んで
an unshakeable feeling, summon a miracle!
こんな私のぜんぶが叫ぶ cry
All of me is crying out,
wish on a shooting star
夢だと言い聞かせる
Telling myself it's just a dream,
あなたとの時間もあの温もりも
our time together and that warmth...
戻りたい 出会った
I want to go back to when we met.
あの時まで二人でもしも
Even if we could go back to that time,
素直なまますべてを言えてたらなんて
if only I'd been honest and said everything...
届けてよ 叶えてよ
Deliver it, make it come true,
消せない気持ち 奇跡を呼んで
an unshakeable feeling, summon a miracle!
こんな私のぜんぶが叫ぶ cry
All of me is crying out,
wish on a shooting star
届けてよ 叶えてよ
Deliver it, make it come true,
消せない気持ち 奇跡を呼んで
an unshakeable feeling, summon a miracle!
こんな私のぜんぶが叫ぶ cry
All of me is crying out,
wish on a shooting star
そばにいて
Stay by my side.
息も止まるほどに
Breathless and frozen,
抱きしめて
hold me tight.
本音は今も このカラダに収まらないよ
My true feelings still can't fit inside this body—
i miss you
届けてよ 叶えてよ
Deliver it, make it come true,
消せない気持ち 奇跡を呼んで
an unshakeable feeling, summon a miracle!
こんな私のぜんぶが叫ぶ cry
All of me is crying out,
wish on a shooting star
例えば僕ら二人 煌めく映画のように 出逢い直せたらどうしたい
For example, if the two of us could meet again like in a sparkling movie scene, what would you want to do?
何も謎めいてない 今日は昨日の続き 日々は続くただぼんやり
Nothing is mysterious; today is just yesterday's continuation, days going by in a blur.
微かな足音 シートの置く場所 それだけですべてわかってしまうよ
Faint footsteps, where we place our seats—that's all it takes to understand everything.
見え透いた嘘も 隠した本当も その全て愛おしかった
Transparent lies and hidden truths, all of it was so dear.
レディー 笑わないで聞いて ハニー 見つめ合っていたくて
Lady, don't laugh, listen. Honey, I just want us to gaze at each other.
君と二人行ったり来たりしたいだけ ベイビー 子供みたいに恋がしたい
I just want to go back and forth with you. Baby, I want to fall in love like a child.
書き散らしていく僕らのストーリーライン
Our hastily scribbled storyline...
例えばどっちか一人 ひどい不幸が襲い 二度と会えなくなったら
For example, if terrible misfortune struck one of us and we could never see each other again,
考えた矢先に 泣いてしまうくらい 日々は続く一層確かに
I'd end up crying just thinking about it—the days go on even more surely.
いつもの暗い顔 チープな戯言 見過ごすようにまた優しいんだろう
You'd kindly look past the usual gloomy face and cheap nonsense once more.
見え透いた嘘も 隠した本当も その目から伝わってきた
Transparent lies and hidden truths, I could feel them all through your eyes.
引っ張ったり 噛み付いたり 傷ついたふりしてみたり 翌日の朝に持ち越したり
Pulling, biting, pretending to be hurt, carrying it over to the next morning,
浮かしたりして 思い切り傷つきたい いつまでもそばにいたい
or letting it float—I want to be hurt to my heart's content, I want to stay by your side forever.
今すぐ行方をくらそう
Let's disappear without a trace right now.
レディー 何も言わないで ハニー 僕の手を取ってくれる
Lady, don't say a word. Honey, won't you take my hand?
君以外に考えられないだけ ベイビー あの頃みたいに恋がしたい
I just can't think of anyone else. Baby, I want to fall in love like back then.
書き散らして踊り続ける
Scribbling hastily, we keep on dancing.
レディー 笑わないで聞いて ハニー 見つめ合っていたくて
Lady, don't laugh, listen. Honey, I just want us to gaze at each other.
君と二人行ったり来たりしたいだけ ベイビー 子供みたいに恋がしたい
I just want to go back and forth with you. Baby, I want to fall in love like a child.
書き散らしていく僕らのストーリーライン
Our hastily scribbled storyline...
例えばどっちか一人 ひどい不幸が襲い 二度と会えなくなったら
For example, if terrible misfortune struck one of us and we could never see each other again,
考えた矢先に 泣いてしまうくらい 日々は続く一層確かに
I'd end up crying just thinking about it—the days go on even more surely.
いつもの暗い顔 チープな戯言 見過ごすようにまた優しいんだろう
You'd kindly look past the usual gloomy face and cheap nonsense once more.
見え透いた嘘も 隠した本当も その全て愛おしかった
Transparent lies and hidden truths, all of it was so dear.
引っ張ったり 噛み付いたり 傷ついたふりしてみたり 翌日の朝に持ち越したり
Pulling, biting, pretending to be hurt, carrying it over to the next morning,
浮かしたりして 思い切り傷つきたい いつまでもそばにいたい
or letting it float—I want to be hurt to my heart's content, I want to stay by your side forever.
今すぐ行方をくらそう
Let's disappear without a trace right now.
見え透いた嘘も 隠した本当も その目から伝わってきた
Transparent lies and hidden truths, I could feel them all through your eyes.
引っ張ったり 噛み付いたり 傷ついたふりしてみたり 明日の朝に持ち越したり 浮かしたりして
Pulling, biting, pretending to be hurt, carrying it over to tomorrow morning, or letting it float...
思い切り傷つきたい いつまでもそばにいたい 今すぐ行方をくらそう
I want to be hurt to my heart's content, I want to stay by your side forever, let's disappear right now!
今すぐ行方をくらそう
Let's disappear right now!
例えば僕ら二人
For example, if the two of us
煌めく映画のように 出会いなおせたらどうしたい
Could meet again like in a glittering movie
何も謎めいてない 今日は昨日の続き
There's nothing mysterious, today is just yesterday's continuation
日数は続くただぼんやり
The days just go on, vaguely
微かな足音 シートの置く場所
Faint footsteps, where the sheets are placed
それだけで全てわかってしまうよ
Just from that, I understand everything
見え透いた嘘も隠した本当も
The transparent lies and the hidden truths
その全て愛おしかった
All of it was so dear to me
レディ 笑わないで聞いて
Lady, don't laugh and listen
ハニー 見つめ合っていたくて
Honey, I just want to gaze at each other
君と二人 行ったり来たりしたいだけ
I just want to go back and forth with you
ベイビー 子供みたいに恋がしたい
Baby, I want to fall in love like a child
書き散らしていく僕らのストーリーライン
Jotting down our story line
例えばどっち一人 ひどい不幸が襲い
For instance, if one of us were struck by misfortune
二度と会えなくなったら
And we could never meet again
考えた矢先に 泣けてしまうくらい
Just thinking about it makes me want to cry
日数は続く一層確かに
Yet the days continue, all the more surely
おい！わー！
Hey! Wow!
ライブが始まってもう 誕生日！誕生日！
The live has started, and it's my birthday! Birthday!
イエーイ！ありがとね、来てくれて。
Yay! Thank you so much for coming.
ということで、今日の配信のハッシュタグは「ラプ様と愉快な仲間たち」！
So, today's stream hashtag is #LaplusAndMerryFriends!
ということで、もちろんゲストがたくさん来るってことー！
And that means, of course, lots of guests are coming!
てことで、それじゃあ、いきます！
So then, let's go!
一心同心ポーズチャレンジ！
Telepathic Pose Challenge!
お題は...
The topic is...
イケメン！
Handsome man!
えっ！？
Huh!?
せーのっ
Ready, set...
おい！
Hey!
えー！？違う違う違う違う！
Eh!? No, no, no, no!
えっ、やってもう一回？
Wait, let's do it again?
私は...きらんってやったの。
I went like... *sparkle*.
え、それイケメンじゃなくてもいいじゃん！
Wait, it doesn't have to be a handsome man!
え、これイケメンだよ。
Eh, this is a handsome man.
え、これ壁ドン？こういうさ、相撲みたいなポーズやってるのかと
Eh, is this wall-don? I thought you were doing a sumo pose...
はっ！？相撲！？壁ドンだわっつって！
Sumo pose!? Wall-don!
いやだからね、やっぱラプ様はイケメンのね、ジャンルがやっぱ違ったか。おい黙れ！
I mean, Laplus-sama's genre of handsome guy was just different. Hey, shut up!
天上天下繋ぐ花火かな
Fireworks connecting heaven and earth
万代と刹那の出逢い
An encounter between eternity and the fleeting moment
忘るまじ 忘るまじ 忘るまじ
Do not forget, do not forget, do not forget
我らの夏を
Our summer
場違いに冷え切った身体を
Releasing a body chilled out of place
人熱に放って
Into the warmth of the crowd
流れ流れ流され思えば 遠くへ来たもんだ
Carried away by the flow, I've come so far
人生なんて飽く気ないね
Life is so ephemeral
まして若さはあちゅう間
Let alone youth, it passes in a blink
今宵全員が魁、一枚目よ
Tonight everyone is a pioneer, the leading star
皆銘々取り取りの衣装 奔放な命を被う化粧
Everyone in various outfits, makeup covering untamed lives
隠すまじ 隠すまじ 隠すまじ
Do not hide, do not hide, do not hide
我らは夏よ
We are summer
皆銘々より取り見取りの衣装
Everyone in an assortment of outfits
乏しい命も休み休みよ
Scanty lives, resting in between
隠すまじ 隠すまじ 隠すまじ
Do not hide, do not hide, do not hide
我らは夏よ
We are summer
何かしら落ち込んだ心は
A heart feeling somewhat depressed
人熱彷徨って 流れ流れ流され思えば 遠くへ来たもんだ
Wandering through the body heat, carried away to far places
永遠なんて素気ないね
Forever is so cold and indifferent
ほんの仮初めが好きね 愈々宴も酣、本番です
Just a fleeting moment is fine
皆銘々選び取り各方向 猛々命燃やす匂ひ
Everyone choosing from all directions, the scent of burning lives
怯すまじ 怯すまじ 怯すまじ
Do not be timid, do not be timid, do not be timid
我らは夏よ
We are summer
皆銘々より取り見取りの衣装
Everyone in an assortment of outfits
乏しい命も休み休みよ
Scanty lives, resting in between
隠すまじ 隠すまじ 隠すまじ
Do not hide, do not hide, do not hide
我らは夏よ
We are summer
一寸女盛を如何しようこの卲り行く行く処がない
What shall I do with the prime of womanhood, with nowhere to go
花盛り 色盛り 真盛り
Full bloom, full color, full prime
一寸大丸の枝垂れ桜 苏る一世の走馬燈
A large weeping willow, a revolving lantern of a single lifetime
逃すまじ 逃すまじ 逃すまじ
Do not let it escape, do not let it escape
我らの夏を
Our summer
丁度一期のしだれ柳
A weeping willow of a lifetime
蘇る一世の走馬燈
A revolving lantern of a single lifetime reviving
逃すまじ 逃すまじ 逃すまじ
Do not let it escape, do not let it escape...
我らの夏を
Our summer.
ちょいと
Hey...
あ ちょいと
Ah, hey...
女盛を如何しよう この間佇む行き場がない
What should we do with the prime of womanhood, with nowhere to go like this?
このままじゃまだ終われないよ
It still cannot end like this!
花盛り 色盛り 真盛り
Full bloom, color bloom, true bloom,
ああ まだ まだ
Ah, still, still...
サヨナラ はじめまして
Goodbye, nice to meet you.
わぁ すみ
Wow, sumi—
やばマジで 俺こんな初めてだよ
Seriously man, this is my first time doing this!
来てくれてありがとうございますね
Thanks for coming!
ありがとう めっちゃ楽しかったわ めっちゃ楽しいマジで
Thanks, it was super fun! Seriously, so much fun!
だってさ いるんだもんそのステージにさ
I mean, you were right there on stage!
こんな別人に正してくれて
And treating me like a totally different person—
こんな俺は経験すると思ってなかったよ マジかよ
I never thought I'd experience something like this. Seriously?!
ありがとうね来てくれて
Thanks for coming!
ありがとうね来てくれて 初めて絡んだのいつか覚えてますか
Do you remember when we first interacted?
あれだよね、いや俺は覚えてるよ。あの俺が普通に平和にダストをしてたらさ、なんか現れてさ、ガキんちょが僕の土地をさ、奪っていってさ
Ah right, well I remember. When I was just peacefully playing Rust, you suddenly appeared, and you little brat stole my land—
違う違う違う、勝手にね、違うんだよ、勝手にね、貸したの、貸してくれたって
No no no, you voluntarily— no, you lent it to me! You said you'd lend it!
言ってねえよ俺、もう分どられたみたいなさ、もう俺の脳みその中でさ
I never said that! It felt like I got mugged in my own mind!
違う、貸してくれて、しかも、あの業務手伝ってくれたり、
No, you lent it to me, and furthermore, you helped with chores—
毎回毎回、さみぃこれ売ってくれって、はい分かりました
Every single time, saying "Samy, sell me this," and I'd say "Okay, understood."
毎回毎回、お前が使うってボイスの、在庫を補充する係をしてたんだ俺は、毎回毎回
Every single time, I was the one restocking your voice lines you wanted to use!
あ、サミィこれ売ってくれって、はいわかりました、売ってあげますって
Oh, "Samy, sell me this," "Okay, understood, I'll sell it to you."
いや、マジで爆売れだったよ
Man, it was a huge bestseller!
ありがとうね、爆売れだったな、ありがとね
Thanks, it really sold like hotcakes. Thank you!
最近は、でもあれじゃない、やっぱり、あの、VCR GTAを一緒にやったのがデカかったね
Lately though, doing VCR GTA together was huge, right?
そうだね、初めて同じチームになってさ、マジ全然やんねえじゃん
That's right, we were in the same team for the first time, and you barely played at all!
俺はあれで、あれじゃないの
Wait, wasn't it because of—
いろんな仲を深めて、僕があなたにロールを
Deepening our bonds, and me teaching you the role—
あ、そう、ロールってなんですか
Oh right, what's a "role"?
はあ！？あんだけ俺は新味に教えたよね、きみに！
Huh?! I taught you with all my sincerity!
ロール？ロールってゲームがあったよ、もう忘れちゃった、記憶から忘れちゃった
Role? There was a game called Role, I forgot, it slipped my mind!
頑張ってって、俺が頑張ってたのを覚えてる / 頑張ってないよ
You worked hard— I remember you working hard. / I didn't work hard!
やめろよ、お前のせいでなんか最近風評被害がやばいんだよ、お前が掘ったんだよ、てか
Stop it, because of you my reputation has taken a hit lately, you're the one who dug it up—
こいつが！こいつのせいです！営業妨害です！
This guy! It's this guy's fault! This is defamation!
この人すぐチャット晒すんで、みんなちゃんと僕から買った方がいいです
This person exposes chats right away, so everyone better buy from me instead!
いやあんなん来たら晒したくなっちゃうじゃん！誰も晒してない！誰も晒す人いないから！
Well when something like that comes, you wanna expose it! Nobody exposed you!
そうだね、今後は気をつけます。はい、よろしく。
That's right, I'll be careful from now on. Yeah, regards.
ありがとうねえ歌ってくれて。 / ありがとうございました。
Thanks for singing with me. / Thank you very much.
ちょっとねカメラ目線面白い / なんて？
Your camera gaze is funny. / What?
ほかのやる気じゃなくてカメラ目線どんどん、やめて！あまいマジでいいって、もう終わりますから
Other people's motivation— no, your camera gaze keeps getting— stop it! Seriously, that's enough, we're wrapping up!
終わりです！バイバイ！ありがと！お疲れバイバイ！ありがと！
It's over! Bye-bye! Thanks! Good work, bye-bye! Thanks!
お題は「VTuber」
The theme is "VTuber".
え！？まじ！？え、まじ！？
Eh?! Seriously?! Eh, seriously?!
せーの！
Ready, go!
音社の
Onsha no...
バリン船長の！
Marine-senchou's!
なんでがはいの格好してんだよ！ / 全然違うよ！
Why are you doing that pose?! / That's completely different!
これVTuberがの配信終わりやるやつ
This is what VTubers do at the end of their streams!
何それ
What is that?
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
この混沌とした令和のインターネットを照らす一筋の光
A ray of light illuminating this chaotic Reiwa internet,
電子の海を漂うオタクに笑顔を 未来の平和をお約束
bringing smiles to the otaku drifting in the electronic sea, a promise of future peace.
躁鬱だけどまかせとけ
Manic-depressive, but leave it to me,
インターネット・エンジェルただいま降臨！
Internet Angel has just descended!
社会をやめろ
Quit society,
家族をやめろ
quit your family,
人間関係をやめろ
quit human relationships!
今すぐ薄暗い部屋で 青白いライトを浴びろ
Bathe in the pale light in a dim room right now!
大丈夫 こわかったこと全部上書きするからね
It's okay, I'll overwrite everything that scared you.
現実よりも crazy for you
More than reality, crazy for you.
おかしくなりそうなほど 情報過多のインターネットを
Saving you from this information-loaded internet
今救い上げてあげる ダーリン ダーリン
that's driving me crazy, darling, darling!
ウソはウソであると見抜けるし この愛は暴走してしまうし 壊れてしまうけど
Even if lies are obvious, this love runs wild and breaks down,
考えなくていいんだよ もうすぐ楽になるから
you don't need to think, you'll feel at ease soon.
もうすぐ楽になるから
You'll feel at ease soon,
脳内に乱反射する poison radio
poison radio scattering in the brain,
麻薬より甘いよ
sweeter than narcotics.
いいね よくないね キミにとっちゃ毒だね
Good, not good, to you it's a poison.
いいね よくないね それでも飲むんだね
Good, not good, still you drink it down.
いいね よくないね 二人の秘密だね 私だけ見ててね
Good, not good, our secret, only look at me.
まるで天使のように微笑み強めの幻覚 internet girl
Smiling like an angel, a strong hallucination internet girl,
そして悪魔みたいにささやくあなただけの needy girl
whispering like a demon, your one and only needy girl.
浅い眠りと承認欲求のオーバーード
Shallow sleep and a validation-seeking overdose,
脳天直撃する私たちだけの宗教と光
religion and light just for us, hitting straight to the brain.
倫理より激しく生きた宇宙すら浸食する恋
A love invading even the cosmos, living more fiercely than ethics.
何度も送られる毒電波を優しさだけで包んで
Wrapping repeatedly sent poison waves solely in kindness,
逆さまのコンピュータと断片的なカウンセリング
upside-down computers and fragmentary counseling.
きらめく屋上で奏でた夢見心地の旋律
A dreamlike melody played on the sparkling rooftop,
夕暮れ時にさよならの練習をして
practicing saying goodbye at dusk.
壊して 愛して 許して 狂って
Break, love, forgive, go mad,
狂って 狂って 甘く狂わせて
go mad, go mad, drive me mad sweetly.
ゆらぎ始める世界 曖昧になる風景 アナタだけが映っているメモリー
The world beginning to sway, scenery becoming vague, memory reflecting only you.
神様なんていないよ このふざけたインターネットは七色のサイケデリック
There is no god, this ridiculous internet is a seven-colored psychedelic.
SNSという瓶詰地獄に救済を 過去の歴史は見ないふりのアナタのためならすぐそばに
Salvation to the bottled hell called SNS, right by your side for you who ignores past history.
このふざけたインターネットは七色のサイケデリック
This ridiculous internet is a seven-colored psychedelic,
SNSという瓶詰地獄に救済を
salvation to the bottled hell called SNS.
過去の歴史は未来に 新たな画面から つけ足してあげる インターネット・エンジェル かわいく生きてね
Adding to future history from a new screen, internet angel, live cutely!
まるで天使のように抱きつく強めのデカいインターネットが欲しくて
Wanting a strong, huge internet hugging like an angel,
悪魔みたいにキスするあなただけのニーディガール
a needy girl who kisses like a demon, only yours.
エンジェル
Angel,
angel,
エンジェル
angel...
Angel,
エンジェル
angel,
angel...
エンジェル
Angel,
angel,
エンジェル
angel...
Angel,
エンジェル
angel,
angel...
はぁ、みんなー！
Haah, everyone!
ペラペラだねー！
You're so thin!
うん、ペラペラだね！
Yeah, paper-thin!
ありがとう！読んでくれて！
Thank you for reading it!
ん、んだよー
Wh-what is it?
ちょっと、ちょっと横向いて。
Hey, turn sideways for a second.
はーい！ペラペラなんだよねー。
Okaaay! You're really paper-thin.
ありがとうね。もうちょっと薄く？
Thank you. Even thinner?
え、私が呼んだからでしょ？ありがとね、ありがとね！
Eh, because I called you, right? Thanks, thanks!
ペラペラでもうれしいよ！
Even if you're paper-thin, I'm happy!
やっぱさ、一体的になってきてほしいよね。
After all, I want us to become one.
そうだね、一体的になって。
That's right, becoming one.
なんで私だけ戻さないの？でもいっぱいやったもんね、ラプちゃん。
Why am I the only one who doesn't get put back? But you did a lot, Lap-chan.
いやマジでお前しかランク青いやついないからさ！
Seriously, you're the only one who doesn't have a blue rank!
しょうがないじゃん！しょうがないからさ、大事にしてね、大事にしてくださいよ。
It can't be helped! Since it can't be helped, cherish me, please cherish me.
え、みんなさ、わがはいと初めて会ったときのこと覚えてる？
Hey everyone, do you remember when you first met me?
プルールさんは？覚えてます！バロラントでしょ？
What about Pururu-san? I remember! Valorant, right?
えーっと、ヒナーノは？
Um, Hinano?
いや、私ももちろん覚えてるよ。バロラントでしょ？
Well, of course I remember too. Valorant, right?
え、バロラントだね。
Uh, Valorant yeah.
今
Now?
今？
うん フラットだとか
Yeah, like flat or...
ていうか絶対いけないもんね
I mean, there's no way you can go.
絶対
No way.
そんなことないよ！絶対ことないよ！
That's not true! Absolutely not!
そんなことないよ
That's not true.
いやー絶対できない
No way, you definitely can't.
ブロンズでしょ？
You're Bronze, right?
今日はシルバー
Today I'm Silver.
シルバーでもいけませんね
Even with Silver, you can't.
この時点で行けないんですよ
At this point, you just can't.
いや最近はあれでしょ？GTA、うん
Well, lately it's been GTA, right? Yeah.
そうだね、最近は
That's right, lately.
GTAね
GTA, huh.
流行りといえばまあGTAね
Speaking of trends, well, GTA.
あとアイコスクイズ
And also the IQ quiz.
あれ知らん？あれの謎のクイズ知らない？
You don't know that? You don't know that weird quiz?
あれ知らん？
You don't know it?
あれめっちゃ面白かったからね
That was super funny, you know.
ね、分かる？
Right, do you know?
アイコ、あ、分かんないって言わないから
IQ— oh, don't say you don't know.
むずかった
It was so hard.
ダイス落ちてたじゃん
Dice were dropped, weren't they?
分かんなかった？
You didn't know?
ドレミがさ、板の覚えてたんだけどさ
Doremi remembered the board, but...
カービィさ
Kirby...
クイズに至るの忘れてたんだよね
She forgot to even get to the quiz.
ひどくない？
Isn't that awful?
俺カービィって言わないのよ
I didn't say Kirby.
いたっけ？
Was she there?
本当にひどい
That's really awful.
いやこいつあのあれだ
Well, this guy...
我が家の給料聞いてきちゃって
Asked about our household salary.
ていうことを思い出して
And remembering that...
いややめて！ひどいの我が家の給料のこと言わないで
No, stop! Don't say awful things about our salary!
直してくれた
He fixed it.
そう直してくれたね、結構
Yeah, he fixed it, pretty much.
優しい
How kind.
昨日の夜結構 めっちゃ呼ばれた時結構
When I was called a lot last night, pretty much...
めっちゃ呼ばれた時きついわ
Being called all the time is tough.
それね
Exactly.
めっちゃお前リフト客じゃん、そう
You were totally a lift passenger, yeah.
リフト客だったわマジで
I really was a lift passenger.
ちゃんと呼ばれた
I got called properly.
よく壊すから
Because you break things a lot.
そうよく壊すからさ
Yeah, because you break things a lot.
めっちゃ放置された
I was totally abandoned.
本当にひどい
That's really terrible.
まあこの気をつけなきゃってことで
Well, gotta be careful about that.
え、でもなんかさ、みんなピンクとかさ赤とかじゃん
Um, but everyone is pink or red, right?
そうだね！
That's right!
我が輩は、我が輩だけ紫色
I am, only I am purple.
ま、でも逆に目立っていいよね、主人公だからさ
Well, but being conspicuous is good, since I'm the protagonist.
主人公だよね、うん
You're the protagonist, yeah.
いやありがとね、みんな
Thanks a lot, everyone.
我が輩に誕生日おめでとうお願いします
Please wish me a happy birthday.
じゃあ
Then...
せーのってする？
Shall we do a "one, two"?
あ、じゃあせーの、おねがいしますよ
Ah, then one, two, please.
してら
When we do it...
せーの！お誕生日おめでとう！お誕生日おめでとう！
One, two! Happy birthday! Happy birthday!
イエーイ！我が輩の体だなぁ
Yay! My body is awesome!
おめでとうおめでとう！
Congratulations, congratulations!
ハラハラするわ今
It's nerve-wracking right now.
我が輩ね、次もやばいんだ
My next part is crazy too.
お前ら 応援してください
You guys, please cheer me on!
応援、応援の気持ちは？
Cheer, what's your cheering spirit?
ラプ様頑張れー
Do your best, Lap-sama!
ちっちゃい声
Such a small voice.
そのガキじゃんまい
That brat is terrible.
おい！やめてね！
Hey! Stop that!
だめだ、こいつらはだめだ
No good, these guys are hopeless.
もう行きます！
I'm going now!
あーやだやだ！
Ah, no way, no way!
バイバーイ！置いてかないで！バイバーイ！バイバーイ！
Bye-bye! Don't leave me behind! Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
心心伝心ポーズチャレンジ！
Telepathic Heart Pose Challenge!
お題は…蛇！
The theme is... Snake!
いやこれはいけるんじゃないか？
Hey, isn't this totally doable?
え、さすがに蛇しかなくね？
Well, obviously it has to be a snake, right?
せーの！
Ready, go!
え？
Eh?
それはわかしてた？
Were you getting hyped just now?
え、違くない？これ、くねくねくね
Huh, isn't that wrong? This is wiggles and squiggles...
え、私はほら、くねくねくね
Eh, look at me, wiggling and squiggling...
え？
Eh?
だからお題よ！蛇なんだよ！
That's why! The theme is a snake!
夢ならば どれほどよかったでしょう
How good it would have been if this were all just a dream
未だにあなたのことを 夢にみる
Even now, I still dream of you
忘れた物を 取りに帰るように
Like I'm going home to get something I've forgotten
古びた思い出の 埃を払う
I dust off my old, worn memories
戻らない幸せがあることを
The last thing you taught me
最後にあなたが 教えてくれた
Is that there are types of happiness that don't come back
言えずに隠していた 昏い過去も
The dark past I kept hidden and unsaid
あなたがいなきゃ 永遠に昏いまま
Would have remained forever dark, if I hadn't met you
きっともうこれ以上 傷つくことなど
I know there's no possible way
ありはしないと 分かっている
I could ever be hurt any more than this
あの日の悲しみさえ あの日の苦しみさえ
Even the sadness of those days, even the pain of those days
そのすべてを愛していた あなたとともに
I loved every bit of it, with you by my side
胸に残り離れない 苦いレモンの匂い
In my heart, never coming out, is the bitter smell of lemon
雨が降り止むまでは 帰れない
I can't go home until the rain lets up
今でもあなたは 私の光
And even now, you're my light
暗闇であなたの背をなぞった
In the darkness, I traced your back
その輪郭を鮮明に覚えている
I remember its outline vividly
受け止めきれないものと出会うたび
Each time I encounter something I can't fully accept
溢れてやまないのは涙だけ
Nothing wells up but my tears
何をしていたの 何を見ていたの
What were you doing? What were you looking at?
私の知らない横顔で
Your face turned to the side, expression unknown
どこかであなたが今 私と同じような
If you're somewhere now, just the way I am
涙にくれ 淋しさの中にいるなら
Trapped in loneliness, suffering and crying
私のことなどどうか忘れてください
Somehow, please, just forget about me
そんなことを心から願うほどに
I wish for it so strongly, with all my heart
夢ならば どれほどよかったでしょう
If it had been a dream, how good it would have been.
未だにあなたのことを夢にみる
Even now, I still dream of you.
忘れた物を取りに帰るように 古びた思い出の埃を払う
Like returning to retrieve something forgotten, I brush the dust off old memories.
戻らない幸せがあることを 最後にあなたが教えてくれた
You taught me in the end that there is happiness that won't return.
言えずに隠してた昏い過去も あなたがいなきゃ永遠に昏いまま
The dark past I kept hidden would have remained dark forever without you.
きっともうこれ以上 傷つくことなど ありはしないと分かっている
I know for sure there will never be anything else to hurt me this much.
あの日の悲しみさえ あの日の苦しみさえ
Even the sorrow of that day, even the pain of that day,
そのすべてを愛してた あなたとともに
I loved all of it, together with you.
胸に残り離れない 苦いレモンの匂い
The bitter smell of lemon lingering in my heart and refusing to leave.
雨が降り止むまでは帰れない
I cannot go home until the rain stops falling.
今でもあなたはわたしの光
Even now, you are my light.
暗闇であなたの背をなぞった その輪郭を鮮明に覚えている
In the darkness, I traced your back, remembering its contour vividly.
受け止めきれないものと出会うたび 溢れてやまないのは涙だけ
Each time I encounter something I cannot accept, only tears overflow endlessly.
何をしていたのか 何を見ていたのか
What was I doing? What was I looking at?
わたしの知らない横顔で
With an unfamiliar profile of yours.
どこかであなたが今 わたしのと同じ様な 涙にくれ 淋しさの中にいるなら
If somewhere you are now, like me, drowning in tears and loneliness,
わたしのことなどどうか忘れてください そんなことを心から願うほどに
Please forget all about me, I wish for it from the bottom of my heart.
今でもあなたはわたしの光
Even now, you are my light.
脱速！
Dasoku!
はいはいはい
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
ちょテンション高くない？
Aren't you a bit too high-tension?
緊張が、緊張解けたね。
The tension's melted away, huh?
緊張解けたね。うん。
Melted away, yeah.
ああ、今日ライブなんですよ、誕生日なんですよ。
Ah, today's our live, it's my birthday!
ああ、おめでとうございます。それに関しては、はい。
Oh, happy birthday! On that front, yes.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
え、初絡みいつですか? 覚えてますか?
Uh, when was our first interaction? Do you remember?
覚えてますよ。あれです、バロラントね?
I remember. That's right, Valorant, right?
本当に? 違うよ! あの
Really? No! That-
あ、そうそうそう。やったんだ。
Ah, right, right, right. You did.
それね! それで、あれだよね、懐かしいね。
That's right! That's when, yeah, how nostalgic.
そこから... そこから... うん。
From there... From there... yeah.
その後GTAかな? 途中ないか。ないないない。
After that, GTA maybe? Wait, was there nothing in between?
GTAで、なんかさ迷っててから
In GTA, I was wandering around, so-
さ迷ってない! さ迷ってから、え、寂しいのかなと思って
I wasn't wandering! Thinking you might be lonely,
雑談だ! で、一緒にね、チームになって
"Let's chat!" and we became a team together,
ビザにしてね、そこから...
got visas, and from there...
うん、楽しい日々を送ったね。
Yeah, we spent fun days together.
本当に思ってる?
Do you really mean that?
ああ。
Yeah.
嘘だ!
You're lying!
思ってないじゃん! 思っ... てないじゃん!
You don't mean it! You don't mean it!
あたま... え? ちょっと待って。え? おお、来てきてくれたのかと思ったよ。違うのかよ!
Wait a minute. Oh, I thought you came to see me. That's not it?!
なんでだよ!
Why'd you say that?!
さ雑魚杯の前にさ、バロラントとプルールと3人でやったの覚えてる?
Before that Zako Cup, remember playing Valorant and Plur and the three of us?
覚えてる、覚えてる。
I remember, I remember.
意味がわかんなかったけど、あの3人でやったの。雑にね、雑に誘ってやったんだけどさ、
I didn't get the point, but we did it as three. I casually invited you, but-
そんときに、なんかみんなVCつけてたのに、なぜか雑魚だけバレた。
At that time, everyone had their VC on, but for some reason only Zako's voice leaked.
そうだよね?
That's right, right?
そう、雑魚さんです。
Yeah, Zako-san.
二人ともまあまあ特徴のある声なのにさ。
Even though both of us have pretty distinct voices!
雑魚だけバレて、そんときの恨みにさ、あの... でもお風呂ってさ...
Only Zako leaked, and holding a grudge from back then... uh, but baths are like...
意味わかんねえよな! だから、え、じゃあ歌おうと思って呼んだ。
That makes no sense! So, uh, I invited you thinking we'd sing.
そこが? じゃあその野良の人のおかげで、これ。
That's why? Then thanks to that random person, this happened.
あ、そうそうそう。だね。
Ah, that's right, that's right.
重いね、それ。
That's heavy.
ありがとぜ!
Thank you!
おー、ね、ありがとね。あの時のあの人。
Oh, right, thanks a lot. That person from back then.
ライブ来てくれてありがと。でも、めっちゃこのスタジオにね、全然似合わなくていいね。
Thanks for coming to the live. I mean, this studio really doesn't suit you at all, it's great!
いや、そんなことないでしょ!
No way, that's not true!
う、歌いてですから、ももと。
Well, I'm a singer originally.
あ、確かに。よし。
Ah, true. Alright.
え、なんかさ、本当にストリーマーだと思ってて。
Eh, like, I honestly thought you were just a streamer.
元々有名歌いてですから、ももと。自分で言うな。
Originally a famous singer, you know. Don't say it yourself!
有名ストリーマーかと思ってたんだけど。
I thought you were a famous streamer.
え、でも歌上手い。
Well, you're good at singing.
歌でやってきましたから僕。15年ぐらいね。
I've been doing this with singing for about 15 years.
え、すご! あ、配信3周年? 3年...
Wow! Ah, 3rd streaming anniversary? 3 years...
まあまあまあ。
Well, well, well.
5倍?
5 times?
いやもう山次があるんで。
Well, there's a next mountain coming up.
バイバイ!
Bye-bye!
雑談じゃねえかよ! え? そんなことないよ! バイバイ! バイバイ! バイバイ!
That wasn't a chat! No way! Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
阿心伝心ポーズチャレンジ
[Ashin Denshin Pose Challenge]
お題 アーティスト
[Topic: Artist]
え！？え！？
What?! What?!
ちょっと待って
Wait a minute.
え、マイク持って手上げてんの？
Eh, you're holding a mic and raising your hand?
そう、私持って手上げてんの
Yeah, I'm holding it and raising my hand.
あーーー！やったーーー！
Ahhh! Yay!
いや、久しぶりにリハした。
Man, it's been a while since we rehearsed.
やっと、やっとお洒落か
Finally... finally fashionable?
easy breezy easy breezy
はい始まった 絡まった
Yeah, it started, getting tangled up,
からかったやつらは どこかに行っちゃった
the teasing guys went off somewhere.
誰に頼まれたわけでもないのに 止まれねぇ
Nobody asked me to, but I can't stop!
筆 ここでは誰もが王様なのだね
Pen—here, everyone is a king, you know.
てか長続きする気がしない
I feel like this won't last long, though,
とかそんな性格で何が悪い
so what's wrong with that kind of personality?
ただ好きなものは好き
I just like what I like,
外野はお黙り キミ無責任 ここ地球、ゼログラビティ
outsiders, be quiet, you're irresponsible. This is Earth, zero gravity!
うっさいなあ ジャマしないでね
How annoying, don't get in my way,
イッパツハデにやってみようやの
let's try doing it with a big splash!
脳みそイマジネーション
Brain full of imagination,
見たもん聞いたもん それ全部血になる
everything I've seen and heard becomes my blood.
飛べる 飛べ！なめさせとけ
Fly, fly! Let them lick their wounds,
頭ん中もう完成形見えた
in my head, I already see the finished form.
頭ん中もう自由自在
In my head, I'm completely free.
心の網目細かくして
Making the mesh of my heart fine,
最強の世界できちゃってるわな～
I've created the ultimate world~
easy breezy easy breezy
一張羅パリッと着込んで
Dressed up sharply in my best outfit,
戦闘モードなんだこりゃ
what is this combat mode?
どうせやるならめんどくさくんなろうぜ
If we're going to do it anyway, let's make it a hassle!
なるようにするのさ easy breezy
Make it happen, easy breezy.
いいもんさ 覚悟決めたなら
It's good, once you've made up your mind,
やったらいいいじゃんどんなもんだ
doing it is great, how do you like that?!
やぶれかぶれでもどうにかこうにかしようぜ
Even if it's desperate, let's manage somehow,
なるようにするのさ easy breezy
make it happen, easy breezy.
easy breezy easy breezy
見切り発車で進んでしまったね
We went ahead with a rash start, didn't we?
街の灯りが後ろに消えてく孤独
The solitude as the city lights fade behind.
手ぶらでもなるようにするのさ 笑
Make it work even empty-handed, haha.
あらもうこんな時間？
Oh, is it already this time?
腹減った ためっちう ラーメン食べちまう
Hungry, let's save it up and eat ramen!
i say hi you say hi もうちょっと待ってな
I say hi, you say hi, wait just a bit longer,
あっチュートリアル完成 するなんて意外
surprising that the tutorial gets finished.
窓開けな鳥、鳴いてるわ こっちへおいでよ
Open the window, birds are singing, come over here.
一面からじゃ見せられないな
Can't show it from just one side,
こっちへおいでよ ちゃんと自分で意識してみて
come over here, try being conscious of it yourself.
ほらどんなもん描こうか こんな色はどうか
Look, what kind of thing should we draw? How about this color?
こいついれればヨウーロだわ
Put this in and it's European!
黄ばんだ目のやつら ばっちい話な、来たら追い払うわ
Yellowish-eyed guys, gross story, if they come I'll chase 'em away.
モーマンタイ無問題
No problem at all, momantai.
あーしらはかわかない
We won't dry out,
とまるつもりないわ
we don't plan on stopping.
easy breezy easy breezy
一張羅パリッと着込んで
Dressed up sharply in my best outfit,
戦闘モードなんだこりゃ
what is this combat mode?
どうせやるならめんどくさくんなろうぜ
If we're going to do it anyway, let's make it a hassle!
なるようにするのさ easy breezy
Make it happen, easy breezy.
いいもんさ 覚悟決めたなら
It's good, once you've made up your mind,
やったらいいいじゃんどんなもんだ
doing it is great, how do you like that?!
答え分かってりゃ苦労なんかしないぜ
If I knew the answers I wouldn't have any trouble,
なるようにするのさ easy breezy
make it happen, easy breezy.
easy breezy easy breezy
お疲れ様
Good job.
だーこどこどこどこ…
Daoko, where, where, where...
ちょっと代わりにやって代わりにやって
Wait, do it instead of me, do it instead of me.
まだ起き上がれてない
I still can't get up.
草生え
Lol.
起きれない 起きれられない
Can't get up, can't get up.
MCパートが待ってますよ
The MC part is waiting for you.
はあ
Haah.
そうだねMCだね
That's right, it's the MC.
だーこが苦手って言ったらしいんだね
Daoko said she's not good at this, right?
あ、やめてね
Ah, stop it.
2人共笑ってんだよ
Both of us are laughing.
私焦ってたなと思って
I was thinking I was panicking.
焦がれていらっしゃったなと思って
You were yearning for it, I thought.
いや、嬉しかったんだよ
No, I was so happy.
いやだってさ、あのずっと分通してたちょん
I mean, you know, we've been penpals for a long time.
そうですね
That's right.
分通友達
Penpal friends.
分通仲間
Penpal buddies.
今日初めて会ったんだよね
We met for the first time today, right?
今日初めてお会いしましたね
We met for the first time today.
なんか嬉しがってる
She seems so happy.
嬉しがって体の表現してくれた 可愛かったね
She expressed her happiness with her whole body. It was cute.
え、なんかさ、ラプラスがさ、あの、だーこと一緒に歌わないかってさ言ったら
Laplus said, "Won't you sing with me, Daoko?" and when she said that...
突然ね
Suddenly, you know.
やるやる！ って言ってくれてさ、だから雪来てくれてありがとうね
She said that, so thank you for coming, Yuki.
いやもうこちらこそありがとうございますもう
No, thank you so much, really!
でしょ？こうのステージかっこいいでしょ？
Right? This stage is cool, isn't it?
あ、めちゃくちゃかっこいい衣装じゃん。
Ah, what a super cool outfit!
え、しかも今日衣装合わせてきてくれたでしょ？
And you even matched outfits with me today, right?
そうなんです。もうラプ様をイメージしていただきまして。
That's right. I made it with Laplus-sama in mind.
わあ、いいじゃん！
Oh, nice!
恭しくしながら わあ、いいじゃんかよ。
With such reverence... Oh, that's great!
でれでれしてる。
You're all flustered.
え、あのさ、正直？
Hey, honestly?
はい。いい？
Yeah. Well?
え、な、え、何ですか？
Wh-What is it?
我が家のこと好きなん？
Do you like my family?
あ！え、ラプさん、何？
Ah! Um, Laplus-san, what?
ラプ様！何？
Laplus-sama! What?
あ、そろそろ時間じゃないですか？
Uh, isn't it almost time?
ごまかした！ごまかした！嘘でしょ！？
You're changing the subject! No way!
好きって言えよ！嘘！なんて！
Just say you like me! Just kidding!
次いかないと、続きはwebで。
We gotta move on, the rest is on the web.
バカ！
Idiot!
しゃあない。
Oh well.
心伝心ポーズチャレンジ、
Telepathic pose challenge,
お題は...
the topic is...
ギャング！
Gang!
はあ！？これは得意なんじゃない？
What?! Aren't you good at this?
なんできたよ？
What do you mean?
だってだよ。
I mean, come on.
せーの！
Ready, go!
うそでしょ！
No way!
なにそれ！？
What is that?!
え、なんか、ほら、オラオラみたいなやつ。
Um, like, you know, the "ora ora" kind of thing.
ああ、それヤンキーや！
Ah, that's a yankee!
それヤンキーや！
That's a yankee!
踊ってるだけで退場
Just dancing makes me leave
それをそっかそっかって言って
Saying "is that so, is that so"
お幸せについて討論
Discussing happiness
何が正義なんかってみんな思う
Thinking about what justice is
生意気そうにガム噛んで
Chewing gum with a cheeky look
それもいいないいなって思う
Thinking "that's not bad either"
テレスコープ越しの感情
Emotions through a telescope
ロッカーに全部詰め込んで
Stuffed entirely into the locker
踊ってない夜を知らない
Don't know a night without dancing
踊ってない夜が気にならない
Don't care about a night without dancing
踊ってない夜を知らない
Don't know a night without dancing
踊ってない夜が気にならない
Don't care about a night without dancing
踊ってない夜なんてもう僕は知らない
I don't know a night without dancing anymore
踊ってない夜なんて夜なんてない夜なんてとってもとっても退屈です
A night without dancing... It's very, very boring
感じたまますぐ行動
Act on whatever you feel
そうすれば音楽も踊り出す
That way music will also start dancing
胸の中で踊る今
Dancing in my heart right now
これはチャンスなんかって思う
Thinking this must be a chance
カーストネット鳴らす連打
The castanet goes "tan tan tata tatan"
タタタタタンタンタタタタン
"tan tatantan tatantan"
踊ってない夜を知らない人とかこの世に一人もいません
There is no one in this world who doesn't know a night without dancing
踊ってない夜を知らない
Don't know a night without dancing
踊ってない夜が気にならない
Don't care about a night without dancing
踊ってない夜を知らない
Don't know a night without dancing
踊ってない夜が気にならない
Don't care about a night without dancing
踊ってない夜なんてもう僕は知らない
I don't know a night without dancing anymore
踊ってない夜なんて夜なんてない夜なんてとってもとっても退屈です
A night without dancing... It's very, very boring
いつも待っている
It's always waiting
ダンスホールは待っている
The dance hall is waiting
変わって変わって傷付いても待っている
Changing, changing, waiting despite being hurt
踊っている未来のダンスホール
Dancing in the future dance hall
未来のダンスホールを彩るその日はあなた、あなた
The one who colors the future dance hall is you, you!
「ダンスホールは君の笑顔を待っている」
"The dance hall is waiting for your smile!"
踊ってない夜を知らない
Don't know a night without dancing
踊ってない夜が気にならない
Don't care about a night without dancing
踊ってない夜を知らない
Don't know a night without dancing
踊ってない夜が気にならない
Don't care about a night without dancing
踊ってない夜なんてもう僕は知らない
I don't know a night without dancing anymore
踊ってない夜なんて夜なんてない夜なんてとってもとっても退屈です
A night without dancing... It's very, very boring
知りたい夜あなたが踊るなら
If you want to dance and know the night
好きになりたい夜あなたが踊るなら
If you want to love and dance the night
知りたい夜あなたが踊るなら
If you want to dance and know the night
踊ってない夜が気にならない
Don't care about a night without dancing
踊ってない夜なんてもう僕は知らない
I don't know a night without dancing anymore
踊ってない夜なんて夜なんてない夜なんてとってもとっても退屈です
A night without dancing... It's very, very boring
踊る夜は大切、とってもとっても大切
Dancing at night is important, very, very important!
踊ってるだけで退場 それをそっかそっかて言って
I walk out of a dance saying "that's it, that's it"
お幸せについて討論 何が正義なんかって思う
Discussing happiness and thinking what justice is
生意気そうにガム噛んで それもいいなないいなって思う
Chewing gum cheekily, I think that's good too
テレスコープ越しの感情 ロッカーに全部詰め込んだ
The telescope is seeing all the emotions in the locker
お前ら頑張れ！
You guys, do your best!
お疲れ様！
Good job!
おっちょだよ、みんな！
Hello everyone, it's Occho!
お疲れ様です！
Good work!
いやー、踊り疲れたよ。
Man, I'm so tired from dancing.
まだまだ、戻って戻って戻って！
Still more, go back, go back, go back!
なんでやるんか...
Why are we doing this...
こんなの作ったの初めてだわ。
It's my first time making something like this.
いや、みんなTシャツ見てよ！
Hey, everyone, look at the T-shirts!
是非これ着てください！ これ！
Please wear this! This one!
どういたしまして！ ありがとう！
You're welcome! Thank you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
革命Tシャツよ。
It's the Kakumei T-shirt.
そうだよ、みんなでGTAブリジャン集まるの？
That's right, everyone's gathering at GTA Burijang?
そうだね、久しぶりだね。
That's right, it's been a while.
久しぶりだね、本当久しぶりだな。
It's been a while, really been a while.
これみんなメンバーじゃない？
Aren't these all members?
いやー、忙しくてね、しょうがないですね、大人だからだよ。
Well, we're busy, can't help it, we're adults after all.
あたりにいる、川崎さん？
Is it Kawasaki-san around there?
見てるか？ 見てるか？
Are you watching? Are you watching?
頑張ってますよ、我々は！
We're working hard!
頑張ってるよ。
We're doing our best.
革命結成順でね、思い出語っていこうと思うんだけど。
Let's talk about it in order of Kakumei's formation, and share memories.
最初わかんないんだよね。え、ぷるるぷるるぷるるだよ。
At first, we didn't get it. Eh, it was Pururu Pururu Pururu.
そう、最初にやって、で、なんかプルルと赤人さんがいて、で、その後3人で釣り仕様って言ってて、
Yeah, first, and then there was Pururu and Akajin, and then the three of us went fishing or something,
なんか駄作とうゆがいて。
Dasaku and Uyu were there.
僕ら刑務所で出会って、悪いことしてるよ。
We met in prison... doing bad things.
悪いことしようよってね。で、駄作知ってたから、駄作！と思って。
Saying let's do bad things. And I knew Dasaku, so I thought, Dasaku!
最初りーてんのあと、なんか知らない人いて、誰！？ってなった。
After Ri-ten, there was someone I didn't know, and I was like, Who is this!?
本当にだって、「お前の名前がローリーか！？」って。「ローリーっていっぱいいるじゃん」だって。
Really, I said, "Is your name Rolley?!" and "There are so many Rolleys."
女の子みたいな... 大体だよな。
Like a girl... Usually, yeah.
いやいや、わかんないよ、女の子かなと思って。
No, no, I didn't know, I thought it was a girl.
で、それであだ名が理して、ギャングやろうぜって。
And then we nicknamed him Rishi and said let's do a gang.
最初「革命」って言ってたの、プルルと、そうだよね、そうだそう、で、革命。
At first, Pururu and I called it "Kakumei", right? Yeah, right, so Kakumei.
そう。ここでもう「革命」は出てたんだよね。
Yeah. "Kakumei" was already mentioned here.
で、ボスを押し付けられた。あ、そうそうそう。
And the boss was forced onto us. Ah, right, right, right.
やっぱ駄作... ぴったり、ぴったりだった。
As expected of Dasaku... It was a perfect fit.
どうぞって言って、そんだな。で、その後、
Go ahead, I said, and then after that,
サミー。
Sammy.
で、ここはほぼ同時ぐらいかな？ ケンクとサミーが同時ぐらい。
And here, it's about the same time? Kenku and Sammy at around the same time.
あ、サミーが先で。
Ah, Sammy was first.
で、ケンクは面接に来た。
And Kenku came for an interview.
面接なの？
An interview?
面接なのよ。
It was an interview.
ケンクが面接に、お前同時だったの？
Kenku came to the interview, were you guys at the same time?
いや、違う違う、俺はちょっと早かったよ。案内やすいしないね、だってね。
No, no, I was a bit early. It wasn't easy to guide, you know.
そうそう、ちょっと同時にしたら入ってたの。
Yeah, yeah, when we did it at the same time, he got in.
サミー。
Sammy.
そ、え、サミーって、誘おうとしたら入ってた。
When we tried to invite Sammy, he was already in.
そっか、懐かしい。
I see, how nostalgic.
ケンクが一番。
Kenku was the first.
ちょっと違って、入って、最後にあの、裏切り者。
It was a bit different, he got in, and finally, the traitor.
あ、はい、裏切り者だ。
Ah, yes, the traitor.
よかったな。
Glad for you.
ちょっと違って。
A bit different.
で、入って、
And got in,
最後にあの、裏切り者。
and finally, the traitor.
あ、はい、裏切り者だ。
Ah, yes, the traitor.
あ、一番最後にいって、一番最初に裏切りました。
Ah, entered last, betrayed first.
確かに、いや、面白かった。
True, man, it was funny.
どんな気持ち、これやったの？
How did you feel doing this?
非常に楽しかったです。
It was a lot of fun.
最初寝てたしな。
You were sleeping at first, though.
確かに、最初寝てたから、そうそう。
True, you were sleeping at first, yeah.
そんな感じで来れる人来ていただきました。 ありがとうございます！
That's how people who could make it came along. Thank you!
めちゃめちゃ楽しかったわ、これ。 めちゃめちゃ楽しかったわ！
This was so much fun. So much fun!
すごい楽しかった！
Super fun!
楽しそうにしてる。
You look like you're having fun.
でもさ、サミーがフリツキくんぐん…フリツキくんぐん？ 構築してっからね、難しかったですね。
But you know, Sammy was doing choreography training... he built it up, so it was hard.
難しかったですが、ありがとね、来てくれて。ありがと！
It was hard, but thanks for coming. Thanks!
みんな一緒に歌ってくれるからね、嬉しかったです。
Everyone sang along with me, I was so happy.
またゲームとかコラボしようね。やりましょう！やりましょう！やりましょう！
Let's collab on games and stuff again. Let's do it!
バイバーイ！ バイバーイ！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
踊ってるだけで退場 それをそっかそっかて言って
I walk out of a dance saying "that's it, that's it"
お幸せについて討論 何が正義なんかって思う
Discussing happiness and thinking what justice is
ってことできた衣装。アウトフィット。
So I changed my outfit.
ニューアウトフィットって、いつものお洋服です。
New outfit, well, it's just my usual clothes.
今日はここまで来てくれてありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for coming here today.
ちょっとゲストがたくさん来たんですけど、この後聞いてほしい曲があって、
We had a lot of guests come, but there's a song I want you to listen to after this,
次はオリジナル楽曲で！
and next is an original song!
本当にちょっとここまで不甲斐ない姿をたくさん見せてたんですけど、
I've shown you a lot of my pathetic sides up until now,
ちょっとセクシーな感じのオリジナル楽曲を聴いていただけたらと思います。
but I hope you'll listen to this slightly sexy original song.
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
死んだみたい まるで遺体
Like I'm dead, like a corpse
煩悩 頭痛い 動けないの苦悩
Worldly desires, headache, unable to move
ねえ あたし 誰か分からない
Hey, I don't know who I am anymore.
ねえ もう抜け出せない やめられないの drop candy
Hey, I can't escape anymore, drop candy.
曖昧に甘い need ああいいの愛 my mind 狂い幸せの一粒
Ambiguously sweet need, a grain of madness.
とろけて それは蜜の味
Melted, that's the taste of honey.
呼呼 壊れちゃった 欲しいの sweet sweet
Hehe, it broke. I want it, sweet sweet.
感じてもう 弾いて狂い狂い honey に堕ちて slow
Feel it already, falling into honey, slow.
あたしイイの したい nigh 快に堕ちて non stop な夜に酔いでい
Drunk on a non-stop night of pleasure.
もっと sweet sweet 夢みたいにもう いいの狂い狂い 感じて flow
More sweet sweet, crazy, feel it flow.
苦い kiss まるで怪物みたい まだ足りないみたい ドロドロにドロ愛
Bitter kiss, like a monster, muddy love.
満たせないの 変われないもう 歪む視界以外 何もない苦悩 苦悩の night
Unfillable night of agony and distortion.
ねえ あたし まるで人間じゃないみたい
Hey, I'm like I'm not even human.
さあどうぞ 曖昧に honey ああいいの快 my mind 狂い幸せの一粒
Ambiguously honey, a grain of madness.
とろけた それは歪の味 呼呼 壊れちゃった
Melted, the taste of distortion. Hehe, it broke.
欲しいの sweet sweet 痺れてもう それは快 honey に堕ちて slow
Falling into honey, slow and numb.
あたしイイの 痛いくらい快に堕ちて non stop な夜に酔いでい
Drunk on a non-stop night of pain and pleasure.
もっと sweet sweet 夢みたいにもう いいの狂い狂い 感じて flow
More sweet sweet, crazy, feel it flow.
苦い kiss まるで怪物みたい まだ足りないみたい ドロドロな世界 抜け出したくて
Like a monster, escaping this muddy world.
はい 吐き出した sweet sweet candy
Yes, coughing up sweet sweet candy.
はっ ラプラスの曲 どうだった？
Ha! How was Laplus's song?
いや気付いた？ そう、新曲です！やった！やったぞ！
Wait, did you notice? That's a new song! Yay!
はい、てことです3本目の新曲「drop candy」です！
Yes, it's my 3rd single, "drop candy"!
1年に1本のペースでオリジナル楽曲が出るということでね、やっと出せました。ありがとね！
Releasing a song once a year, I finally put it out!
作詞作曲編曲はbizでのお两个人です。えらいだろ！いっぱい聴いてくださいね！
Lyrics and music by biz! Please listen to it a lot!
ではここで最後の告知タイムをさせていただきたいです。ちょっとね、最後の方にはあの、いい、いいものがみれるのでぜひ最後まで見ていってください。では、告知をします！
Now for the final announcements, watch till the end!
まずはフルセット！これが全部です！これが我が輩の全て！
First is the full set! This is everything of me!
ゲームが上手くなりそうなワイドラバーマット！イラストはさまたる先生で我が輩があのなんかデスクで銃を構えているイラスト。銃を構えている…あ、銃銃誰？ちょっと待って。え、ばっ、てことでイラストはさまたる先生で、我が輩がデスクで銃を構えているかっこいいイラストです。ちょっとイラストは違うんですけど3年目でやっと出せた新衣装で、あの描いていただきました。サイズもね、こんくらいあるんで、ぜひお願いします。ゲームが上手くなるはず！
First, a wide rubber mat of me posing with a gun!
ラプラスを強制的に笑わせることができるボイスキーホルダー。ラプラス・ダークネスの笑い声4種収録！イラストはいつもなしろこ先生で、えっとね、ま、笑、こ、笑っているのが分かると思うんですけどね、4パターン笑い声を収録したので全部聞いてください。あの、押すとね、ボイスキーホルダー押すと我が輩が笑うという仕組みになってますんで、ぜひ聴いてね！
Next, a voice keychain that makes me laugh.
我が輩の茶碗！ちょっと、違うような名前は、コマンダーインチーフスライスボール！てことで、我が輩のね、デザインが入ったお茶碗であります。
Next, the Commander-in-Chief's Rice Bowl!
運命のダイス、Dice of Fate。あ、まあこれなぜか、まあちょっと、あの3個入ってるんです。なぜかね。
And the Dice of Fate, with three included!
よく知らないけど3個ついてます。セットです。
I don't really know why, but you get three. It's a set.
いわゆるですね、わがはいのイメージのモチーフです。かっこいいですね。
It's basically styled after my image. Pretty cool, right?
はい、そして次はこちら！
Yep, and next up is this!
ボイス！えーと、通話しながら寝落ちボイス
Voice pack! Um, a "falling asleep while on call"
ASMRです。もうこれはね…、ASMR、いや、まあいいや、次！次！
ASMR voice. Well, this is... ASMR—well, whatever, next! Next!
次、フルセット購入特典、こちら！えーっと、沙マコ先生の描きおろしポストカードで、
Next, the full set bonus, this! Um, it's a freshly drawn postcard by Samako-sensei,
今回は箔押しのサインとメッセージが入っています。
featuring foil-stamped signatures and messages this time.
えーっとですね、前回、前々回と2回連続で、えっとサイン、直筆サインをやったらもう大変なことになってしまって、本当に死んでしまったので、
Um, you see, the last two times in a row, if I did autographs, handwritten autographs, it became such a disaster and I literally almost died,
今回はサインはお休みです。
so this time autographs are taking a break.
しかし、特典ボイスが2種類付きます。「ダイスゲームボイス」と「ダイスを振る時の掛け声ボイス」！
However, you get two kinds of bonus voices! "Dice game voice" and "Dice throwing cheering voice"!
ということで、なんとなく分かるよね？
So, you kinda get the idea, right?
今回ね、もちゃわんとサイコロがあるんだけど、このふたつがあれば…あれができるよね！そう、チンチロだよね！
This time, we have a rice bowl and dice, and if you have these two... you can do that thing! That's right, Chinchiro!
昨年のね、スタサバで、あの、やりました大人気のチンチロ、まあ、わがはいが大乱暴をしたチンチロをみんなにもやってほしいなと思って。
Last year at Stasaba, we did that super popular Chinchiro, well, the Chinchiro where I went on a rampage, and I thought I'd want everyone else to try it too.
え、なになに？チンチロのやり方がわからない？
Huh, what's that? You don't know how to play Chinchiro?
あーまあ、そういう人もねいると思ったんでね、テストプレイの動画を用意してます。
Ah, well, I figured there might be people like that, so I've prepared a test play video.
はい、ということでこちらどうぞー！
Yep, so with that said, here it is!
なんてここでこれなんだよ？
Why are we even doing this here?
意味がわからない。
I don't get the point.
なんんで俺たちはこれをやらされる？
Why do we have to do this?
お前やったことある？
Have you ever done this?
いや俺ないんだよ、今回初めてだから。
No, I haven't. This is my first time.
あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, is that so?
ちょっと教えを乞いたいんだよ。
I want to ask for some guidance.
らしい。
Apparently.
チンチロだもんね。そうね。
It's Chinchiro, after all. Right.
わからんか、ルール。
You don't get the rules?
わからんのですよ。
I really don't.
ルールわからんか、私は。
You don't know the rules? Me neither.
俺はわかるけどね、やっぱちょっと教えてもらえたらなというのはあるよね。
I get it, but you know, it'd be nice to have someone teach us.
わかんない人いると思うんで、ちょっと、今日この
I figured there are people who don't get it, so today, for this...
チンチロのルールを説明するためだけにきました。
I came here solely to explain the rules of Chinchiro.
お願いします。非常にシンプルです。はい。
Thank you. It's very simple. Yes.
それぞれ3回までサイコロ（3個）を振って出た目の役で勝負。
Each player rolls 3 dice up to 3 times, competing with the hand they get.
強い役を出せば勝利。
Get a stronger hand to win.
なるほど。なるほどね。
I see. I see.
なんで今日2人には、ま、2敗で勝負してもらおうかなと。
So today, for you two, well, I'll have you battle with two losses.
わかりました。わかりましたよ。
Understood. We understand.
勝ち負けがないとさ、勝ち負けが起きたときにちょ緊張感的なのが
If there's no winning or losing, you know, when a win or loss happens, that sort of tension...
キリツクやつね？
Like a discipline thing?
切り札何かが欲しいかもな。
You'd want something like that.
なにもないとね、まあ、ただの運芸になって
If there's nothing, well, it just becomes pure RNG where you go
勝った！ってなるだけだから、
"Ah, I won!", so...
はい。
Yes.
何か、なんかね、何か、なにか！
Something, like... something, anything!
あれ、負けた人が、わがはいのモノマネで
The person who loses... does an impersonation of me...
なんだよ！
What is that?!
やりましょう。
Let's do it.
やだ！
No way.
え、こんなの負けたらもう致命傷や。お前あけとかくてよ！
Huh, if you lose something like this, it's a fatal wound! Disclose it, you idiot!
もうあの役目終わったんで。
My role is already over.
おかしいだろ。
That's weird.
いやだ！やだ！やだやりたくない！お前いやだ！やりたくない！お前もやりたくない！
No! No! I don't wanna do it! I don't want to! You too! I don't want to do it!
座れ！
Sit down!
何回見てるのに一人だれからって思われる。
You'd think someone is looking at it multiple times.
役の強さで一番食らったやつがモノマネです。2敗にしよう。
The one who gets hit with the worst hand does the impersonation. Let's make it two losses.
1回負けてもいいことにしよう。
Let's say it's fine no matter how many times you lose.
怖い。
Scary.
え！？
Huh?!
緊張、緊張でこれ落ちてしまった。
Out of tension, it fell out.
あれ、これ、ションベンか？
Wait, is this a foul roll?
落ちてしまった。緊張ションベン
It dropped. Nervous foul roll!
でも出てても、ひふみのほうが下なんだ。123出たら、これよりやばい。
But even if they come out, 1-2-3 is lower. If you roll 1-2-3, it's worse than this.
まあ、そうか。
Well, true.
行くぞ。
Here we go.
落とさないから、俺をな。
Don't drop me, alright?
はい。
Okay.
しっかり握って。あ、555、5です。
Grip it tight. Ah, 5-5-5, it's 5s.
いやいやいやいや、役出たら終わりやって。
No no no no, once you get a hand, it's over.
なるほどね。
I see.
危なかった。
That was close.
いや、僕も3回振ります。
Well, I'll roll 3 times too.
はい。
Okay.
僕ちょっと役とかあまりわかんないんでちょっと教えていただいて
I don't really know the hands well, so could you teach me—
おい、やめろ、触るな俺に！
Hey, cut it out, don't touch me!
本当に怒られた。
He actually got mad.
つえー！
Strong!
俺の負けで終わりじゃんこれ一個。
My loss is already decided with just this one.
よっしゃ！
Yes!
うわ、強いよ！
Wow, that's strong!
ナイス！
Nice!
お願い。
Please.
1!よええ！1！よええ！
1! So weak! 1! So weak!
行かせていただきます。
I'll take my turn.
まだ役なしがありますからね。
You still have no-hand rolls, after all.
つえー！
Strong!
リーチ！
Reach!
いいんだよ！
It's fine!
日中！
During the day!
決めよっか。
Let's decide.
いきます。
Here we go.
うわ、すごっ！
Whoa, nice!
やった！
Yay!
やった！我が輩やったぞ！我が輩やりました！
Yay! Wagahai did it! Wagahai won!
5！
5!
並んだ！並んだ！5！よし！並んだ！
It matched! It matched! 5! Yes! It matched!
うわ、みって！
Whoa, look!
我が輩じゃん！我が輩じゃん、まじで！
It's Wagahai! It's Wagahai, seriously!
最悪5以上じゃん。
Worst case, it's 5 or higher.
作れる。
We can make it.
いきます。
Here we go.
うわ、やばっ！
Whoa, crap!
下がって！下がって！
Get back! Get back!
うわっ、かった！
Whoa, I won!
かった！かった！かったんだ！
I won! I won! I won!
俺たち勝ったんだ！やった！やった！ありがとう！
We won! Yay! Yay! Thank you!
うぇーい！やった！
Woohoo! Yay!
しゃあ！
Yes!
うるさっ！うるさっ！うるさっ！うるさっ！うるさっ！
So loud! So loud! So loud! So loud! So loud!
やった！
Yay!
うるさっ！我が輩やだ！うるさっ！うるさっ！
So loud! Wagahai hates this! So loud! So loud!
早く行け！早く行け！早く行け！
Go already! Go already! Go already!
3、2、1
3, 2, 1
我が輩はラプラスダークネスである！
I am Laplus Darknesss!
あははははははははははは！
Hahahahahahaha!
という感じでね、気軽に遊べるチェンチェロのグッズとチェンチェロのボイスも
And so, goods for "Chenchelo" which you can easily play with, and Chenchelo's voice, are also available,
入っているので、ぜひフルセットで購入して、お友達がいる人は我が輩の、えっと、モノマネモノマネをかけて戦ってください。
so please definitely purchase the full set, and if you have friends, please battle using Wagahai's, um, impersonations!
何そんなに嫌だったね？何でそんなみんな嫌がってたの？おい！
Why were you guys hating it so much? Why did everyone hate it so much? Hey!
我が輩のフルセットだからですって。
Because it's Wagahai's full set, you say?
ぷへへへへ…
Puhehehe...
という感じでした！改めて、今日は我が輩の誕生日、みんな祝ってくれてありがとうね！
That was it! Once again, thank you everyone for celebrating Wagahai's birthday today!
じゃ、ばいばーい！
Well then, bye-bye!